Matthew Young

♥ Foster City, California ▼ y.matt12@gmail.com 🗖 linkedin.com/in/matthew-young-07 📤 matthewyoung777.gitlab.io/portfolio/

SUMMARY

Full-stack software engineer with experience in Python, JavaScript, and Java. Skilled in back-end development using Django, Fast API, and PostgreSQL, as well as front-end development with React.js. Experienced in system design using Docker and microservices.

SKILLS

Technical Skills: JavaScript, Python, Java, Django, Fast API, Docker, React.js, Node.js, SQL, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, Git, Gitlab, Heroku

Industry Knowledge: Agile Methodologies, Software Engineering, Algorithms, Unit Testing, Object-Oriented Programming, Data Analysis, Data Science

Interpersonal Skills: Teamwork, Communication, Problem solving, Adaptability, Quick Learning, Leadership

PROJECTS

Paper Stonks

Hackreactor · https://gitlab.com/apex-legends1/paper-stonks · October 2022 - December 2022

- · Developed a web-based mock stock trading application simulating investment portfolios and stock trading using real-time stock price data.
- · Orchestrated the creation of a highly scalable and secure REST API powered by Fast API to facilitate seamless data access.
- · Crafted engaging and interactive user interfaces using React.js, integrated with real-time stock data visualization through Chart.js.
- · Spearheaded the implementation of Docker-based microservice architectures for efficient deployment and scalability.
- · Developed GitLab CI/CD automation pipeline while leading a 5-member team to meet project goals.

Car Car

Hackreactor · https://gitlab.com/matthewyoung777/project-beta · September 2022 - October 2022

- · Engineered a web app streamlining interactions between a dealership and its clientele, inventory tracking, vehicle sales, service appointments.
- · Crafted a dynamic and user-friendly front-end UI with React.js, focusing on the appointment microservice for enhanced user engagement.
- · Implemented a robust RESTful API for seamless data access within the appointment microservice with Django.
- · Held Scrum of scrums for discussing daily progress and sprint goals amongst the team, collaborating with Git version control.
- · Designed and executed a scalable data model and microservices structure, with Django and Docker for performance and deployment efficiency.

EXPERIENCE

Autonomous Vehicle Test Specialist

Cruise

July 2021 - July 2022, San Francisco, CA

- · Increased drivable testing zones by 50% through lane and route mapping techniques.
- · Pinpointed and communicated problematic drive behavior data with engineers to reduce driving error frequency by 30%.
- $\cdot \text{ Trained fleet operators introducing new techniques for vehicle testing which increased driverless mileage accumulation by 100\%.}$

Autonomous Vehicle Trainer

Cruise

November 2019 - July 2021, San Francisco, CA

- $\cdot \ \text{Implied safety-focused methods to accumulate autonomously driven mileage for self-driving fleet.}$
- · Curated drive quality and behavioral data for later optimization to engineering.
- \cdot Produced highest autonomous engagement ratio (90%) in the morning cohort.

EDUCATION

Software Engineering

Hack Reactor · San Francisco, CA · November 2022

Bachelor of Arts - BA, Economics

University of Washington · Seattle, WA · 2019

 \cdot Dean's List recognition for 7 quarters

CERTIFICATIONS

SQL for Data Science

Coursera · 2019